everscale has its own nft standard
У everscale есть свой собственный стандарт nft,
called tip 4 or true nft which is a
называемый советом 4 или истинным nft, который является
product of collaboration between all the
продуктом сотрудничества между всеми
everscale developers and teams on the
разработчиками everscale и командами в
network how does it work from a
сети. как это работает с
technical standpoint the first and most
технической точки зрения? первое и наиболее
obvious difference of nfts on everscale
очевидное отличие nfts от
is the storage of information unlike
everscale — это  В отличие от
ethereum where one smart contract stores
Эфириума, где один смарт-контракт хранит
everything about the owner traits and
все о свойствах владельца и
metadatas of the nft collection
метаданных коллекции nft,
everscale follows a distributed paradigm
everscale следует распределенной парадигме,
each nft is a small smart contract with
каждый nft — это небольшой смарт-контракт со
its owner and each nft collection has
своим владельцем, и каждая коллекция nft имеет
one smart contract that stores all
один смарт-контракт, в котором хранится вся
information about the collection there
информация о коллекции.
are also smart contract indexes for each
также являются индексами смарт-контрактов для каждого
nft each wallet has its own end index
nft, каждый кошелек имеет свой собственный конечный индекс,
and each collection has its own index
и каждая коллекция имеет свой собственный индекс,
which enables fast on chain searches we
который обеспечивает быстрый поиск в цепочке, мы
can quickly find all collections all
можем быстро найти все коллекции все
collections with the same code hash all
коллекции с одинаковым хэшем кода все
nfts of one particular wallet and all
nft одного конкретного кошелька и все
nfts of the wallet with the collection
nft  кошелька с
filter another important feature is
фильтром коллекции еще одной важной особенностью являются
small fees for keeping a smart contract
небольшие комиссии за хранение  смарт-контракт
alive everscale requires payment for
live everscale требует оплаты за
data storage of every smart contract nft
хранение данных каждого индекса смарт-контракта nft
index or regular wallet however the fees
или обычного кошелька, однако
are really small for example storage of
комиссии действительно малы, например,
the punk
хранение панк-
number 294 nft costs its owner about
номера 294 nft обходится его владельцу примерно в
0.075 ever per year the collection's
0,075 в год,
author also pays for storage but if
автор сборника также платит за хранение, но если
something happens to the collection's
что-то случится с контрактом коллекции,
contract the nft of this collection
nft этой коллекции
won't be affected the last feature is
не пострадает. Последняя особенность
the cost of issuance and speed of the
— стоимость выпуска и скорость
blockchain everscale is one of the
блокчейна.
too tip 4 is a big step forward for the
4 — это большой шаг вперед для
ecosystem and all wallets on everscale
экосистемы, и все кошельки в Everscale
are going to support it
будут его поддерживать.